*Piano music*
Good morning church. Good morning. I gotta apologize before we get started. Donovan's leaving I think though, so that's okay.
I've had some sniffles, so if I sniff one to the microphone, I'm maybe not as good as Dr. Kumar.
So bear with me. Don't leave, but bear with me.
This morning, oh, for those of you that don't know me, my name is Corey Smith and I have the privilege of
serving on the teaching team here at Canvas Community Church. So if this is your first time, welcome.
Glad you're here with us. We've kind of been going through, as you can see in the slide there, our summer series in the Book of Psalms.
We're gonna take a little detour today, maybe better said, we're gonna be diving into a mini-series within the series
on a special collection of books known as the Psalms of Ascent. These 15 Psalms, which we'll start in today and ending at, well, we're starting 120
and we'll end at 134 today. Provide a historical worship set for the people of God as they traveled together to Jerusalem.
We'll see these, and there's a lot of tongue twisters today, so again, bear with me. Psalms, songs, it's the whole thing.
So you might get a, you might guess, you guys might get a laugh out of it today.
But these Psalms, they provide a historical worship set for people as they traveled together to Jerusalem.
As we'll see, these Psalms were songs of travelers, not just solo adventurers, but whole communities making the journey together
from wherever they were to worship the maker of heaven and earth in Jerusalem.
And as we talk about journeys this morning, I can't help but think that some of our regular attenders may be watching
from the mountains or the beach or wherever your summer travels have taken you.
I think some journeys, like vacations or bucket lists, trips,
you plan for months.
You've got the itinerary, you've mapped the route, you've made the packing list and the playlist,
and you can't wait to just get started.
But other journeys that I think people in the room have probably experienced, maybe even bigger journeys,
begin because something inside you says, I just can't stay here anymore.
You may not know exactly where you're going yet, but you know you just can't stay put.
And I don't know where you find yourself today, and I don't know what kind of journey you've been on lately,
but my hope, and I know it sounds cliche, so I acknowledge that,
is that you'll view this life as a journey.
And more specifically, as a follower of Jesus,
that you'll view this life as a journey with God and his community.
Some trips have destinations that are worth every step.
Others, the journey itself has been better than the arrival.
And sometimes, if we're honest,
either the road or the destination has lived up to the expectation.
But here's the thing I've learned.
When I look back on trips, the things I remember most aren't the pictures at the end.
They're a nice reminder.
But typically, for me,
they're the moments along the way.
The conversations in the car,
the wrong turns that became unexpected detours,
the laughter, the jokes,
even the arguments
that, strangely enough,
drew us closer.
Now, Samantha hates when I say this,
but it's less about the destination
and more about the journey.
To be honest,
she hates it because I usually say it sarcastically
when I veer off course to go to the place I want to go.
Not that she doesn't want to go to the places I want to go,
but I typically tend to be more sporadic than she is.
But if you haven't caught on to the metaphor I'm trying to draw out,
it's this,
that the Christian life,
this life of following Jesus,
is a pilgrimage.
It's a journey.
And like most pilgrimages,
it's far more about the journey
than simply arriving at the destination.
Now, don't misunderstand me.
The destination matters, right?
But it's not ours to control.
See, the destination for the follower of Jesus
is the city of God,
the resurrection of the body,
and the final joy of his presence.
That's in God's hands.
That's his domain, right?
We're comfortable with that.
What I think is in our hands, though,
is the journey.
The miles.
Conversations.
The prayers.
And the tears.
The moments when your feet may feel steady.
And also the moments
where you feel like the road might be endless.
Those are ours to walk together
as a covenant people of God.
And here's the thing about a journey.
God shapes us on the road.
The Christian life is not just about
sitting on the side of the road
and waiting for heaven.
Amen.
No.
No, this journey,
the pilgrimage,
is meant to form us
as followers of Jesus along the way.
We can either be people
who beeline to the destination,
or we can be people
who take in the beauty and sights along the way,
making time for rest stops
and pictures
and take time
and make room for the lessons
that God has for us.
I believe God has called us
to be pilgrims
and not just tourists
in this journey.
And that's the heart posture
I want to bring to the message today.
And it's why I think it's good
to park our cart here
at the Psalms of Ascent.
See, a tourist goes sightseeing
and focuses on the sights around them.
We've all been there, right?
But a pilgrim
sets out to discover
themselves.
The tourist
takes a vacation
to get away
from the life
of who they normally are.
A pilgrim
travels to find out
who they really are.
A tourist grows
their collection of photographs
and souvenirs,
but a pilgrim,
I would argue,
grows in their love of Jesus.
A tourist
never affects
any real change
in their environment,
the place they visit.
But a pilgrim,
a pilgrim works
to see God's presence
in every destination
they touch.
So this journey,
and as we walk
through the Psalms
of Ascent together,
I would ask you
to wrestle with this question.
Am I a tourist
or am I a pilgrim
in this life
that Jesus has called me to?
See, as we'll see today,
these songs
were written for travelers.
They're road songs
for the soul.
They help us to remember
that the walk itself,
the days,
the seasons,
and the companions
along the way
is where God
does some of his best work.
These 15 Psalms,
again,
Psalm 120 to 134,
these are the traveling songs
of God's people.
They were sung
by pilgrims
on their way
up to Jerusalem
for the great feast,
Passover,
Pentecost,
and the Feast of Tabernacles.
So while scholars
would argue over
what ascent really means
in the context
of the Psalms,
the most widely supported idea
is that these were songs
sung
and prayed
by pilgrims
on their way
to Jerusalem
for the feast.
No matter where
these pilgrims
were coming from,
their journey
would have an ascent
towards Jerusalem
because it's situated
on the topographical
high point.
But not only
did it sit physically
on the high point,
it also represents
a spiritual high point,
the place where God
chose to dwell
with his people.
See,
these journeying prayers
provided a soundtrack
for God's people.
confession time.
This is for me,
not for you all.
You guys are good church people.
But those,
these playlists
are probably more
God-honoring
than our typical playlists.
But I digress.
These 15 Psalms
were a soundtrack,
a worship set
for the people of God,
a people on journey.
These Psalms reminded
the people
of their nomadic roots
in Abraham
and the liberation journey
of the Exodus
with Moses.
These pilgrimages
served as a reminder
to God's people
that they were
a pilgrim people
on journey with God.
Invite us to think
about these Psalms
as we go through this
the same way.
They remind us
that our life
with God
is a journey.
It's a journey with God,
but it's also a journey
with his people
on our way
to God's eternal kingdom.
The writer of Hebrews
describes God's people
as foreigners
and strangers
looking for a country
of their own.
I invite us
to think about it
the same way
and join in the Psalms
of Ascent
and sing praise
and pray a soundtrack
for the pilgrimage
of our life
with God
not to physical Jerusalem
but to the eternal country
of new heaven and earth
that lie before us
with God.
I think if you're in it
and I just finished
a spiritual formation class
so I'm all about
imagining stuff.
I think you can picture
whole families
and villages
setting out together
sandals
hitting the dirt
children
running ahead
elders
leaning on staffs
for support
but voices
lifting up
in unison.
Here's the thing
pilgrimage
is not just
about the arrival.
The journey
itself
was part
of the formation.
Worship
didn't start
when they stepped
into the temple
courts.
Now
the worship
started when they
stepped out
of their front door
because here's
what we neglect
to think about
on our journey.
This is what I neglect
to think about
that the road
is holy
ground too.
I intentionally
try to get you
to see that connection
today
the parallelism
there
because we don't
pack a bag
three times a year
and head
to Jerusalem
for a feast.
Now we have
cars
not caravans
we have
GPS's
not dusty road
dusty foot pass
in the Judean desert
and most of us
have never
actually considered
a literal pilgrimage
in our entire lives
but the truth
is
if you claim
Jesus as Lord
you are on
a pilgrimage
right now.
The New Testament
again
consistently calls
us sojourners
and exiles.
We should be
seeing ourselves
as citizens
of another country
walking towards
a city
that God
himself
is building.
Here's the hard
truth
potential reality
check
if you will.
Sunday morning
is not
the destination
it's a mile
marker
on a much
longer road
of serving God
Sunday morning
is not the goal
it should not
be viewed
as the goal
it is a rest stop
what that means
and I put it
in your own context
what that means
is that your
small group
your conversations
with God
over the kitchen
sink
on Tuesday morning
your testimony
at work
to a world
that needs
hope
these are
all small
steps
on our
journey
again
the ancient
Israelites
didn't wait
till they got
to the temple
to start
their journey
no
they sang
on the road
because they
understood
that the road
the journey
was part
of their
worship
to God
in the same
way
the Christian
life is not
about getting
to the end
the Psalms
of Ascent
remind us
that discipleship
is not
a classroom
we sit
in
but instead
a road
we walk
together
so we're
formed not
just by the
truth of the
destination
but by the
grace and
mercy
and yes
the hardships
we encounter
along the way
so the walking
the waiting
the stumbling
the helping
each other up
is where
discipleship
happens
so the road
shapes us
and how God
uses the road
to conform us
more into the
image of the
son I believe
I'm gonna get
on my soapbox
real quick
here's the
theory I've
wrestled with
and
do with this
what you will
but alluding
back to this
idea of
destination
as the
journey
right
is
I fear
we've lost
sight of the
journey
because of
the
destination
because we
say things
and this
isn't a bad
thing right
but we
say things
like I
trust God
to take
care of
me
after I
die
and
whatever
happens
to me
is in
God's
hands
after I'm
gone
and I
get that
I do
not
not saying
that's a
bad
thing
but also
I think
it's because
subconsciously
we realize
we don't
have any
control
over death
we might
be able
to medicate
it
we might
be able
to prolong
it
but ultimately
we know
we don't
have any
control over
I believe
it's an
enemy of
God
so it's
easier and
more comfortable
to say I'll
live with
God
not a bad
thought
but I'll
pose this
question and
do with it
what you
will
what if
we trusted
God not
only with
the things
we can't
control
but also
with the
things we
can
what if
I trusted
him along
the journey
and not
just with
the destination
what if
I trusted
him with
my life
and not
just the
afterlife
because when
you think
about it
the moment
of arrival
is just
one part
of the
story
but typically
we are
guilty of
as Christians
we make
it the
whole story
don't we
the rest
of the
story
the prologue
the one
we're living
in right
now
the one
where we're
on the
road
and trust
me when
I say
brothers
and sisters
that God
is as
active
now
and is
present
now
and is
worthy
of our
praise
here on
this
road
as he
is
when we
reach
our
destination
I'm gonna
say it
again
because I
want this
to set
in
God
is as
active
I told you
tongue twisters
and is
present
worthy
of our
praise
and
obedience
now
here
on this
road
as he
is
when we
reach
our
destination
do we
believe
that
truth
do we
journey
in that
truth
because
if we
do I
think it
changes
things
it means
the ordinary
moments
matter
now
it means
that the
road
you're
on
right
now
the one
that feels
too steep
or too
quiet
long
is still
holy ground
that can be
offered to
God as
worship
it means
that we
can worship
with hope
not just
when we've
arrived
but in
the midst
of our
suffering
and our
hardships
doubts
we don't
have to
wait
to worship
when we've
arrived
but we
worship
with every
step
we take
towards our
creator
redeemer
father
and king
and I think
this is exactly
where psalm
120 begins
that first step
out the door
out of someone's
house
not in the
temple courts
where you've
chosen to
step out
in pilgrimage
and the hot
sun hits
your face
and the dust
of the cloud
of witnesses
is forming
because they've
already started
walking
it's a place
of longing
of restlessness
and an honest
cry of a heart
saying I
cannot live
like this
anymore
God
I need you
so the words
are going to
be up here
on the screen
but in the
heart of
community
and a
on journey
I would ask
you that
you stand
with me
in a posture
of communal
pilgrimage
if you're
able
and let's
read psalm
120 together
I'm going to
start
congregations
part is
going to
be in
the bold
I call
on the
Lord in
my distress
and he
answers me
what
what will
he do
to you
and what
more
besides
you
deceitful
tongue
woe to me
that I
live in
the
that I
dwell
in
Meshach
that I
live
among the
tents
of
Kedar
together
I
am for
peace
but when
I
speak
they
are for
war
you may
be
seated
this is
the word
of the
Lord
notice
where the
psalmist
starts
again
not at
the temple
gates
not in
comfort
safety
but in
distress
this I
think is
the reality
of the
first step
on the
road to
discipleship
it's often
uncomfortable
see the
journey
doesn't
begin
because
everything
is
perfect
the
journey
doesn't
begin
with a
promise
that you'll
get
everything
you've
ever
wanted
the
journey
doesn't
begin
because
you've
had all
your
questions
answered
no
the
journey
begins
because
we
recognize
cannot
stay
where
calling
us
elsewhere
the
psalmist
goes on
to describe
the life
of the
people
of
Meshach
and
Kadar
these
names
appear
in the
book
of
Genesis
Meshach
a
descendant
of
Japheth
and
Kadar
a son
of
Ishmael
to
these
names
they
would
symbolize
exile
danger
and
living
among
hostility
and
corruption
with
the
recognition
of
these
harsh
realities
we're
called
into
a
deeper
participation
with
God
I
think
and
the
understanding
of
the
need
of
God's
intervention
and
guidance
in our
lives
it
calls
us
as
believers
to
seek
peace
and
truth
in a
world
that
often
opposes
those
values
that
sound
familiar
that
is that
foreign
for
anyone
the
road
of
faith
often
takes
us
through
places
like
that
places
where
our
beliefs
are
challenged
our
patience
is
tested
and
where
our
integrity
is
constantly
under
siege
by the
enemy
that
is
the
dusty
road
and
yet
the
psalmist
doesn't
despair
they
might
lament
but
they
don't
despair
they
call
out
and
God
answers
I want you to think back to Jill's message last week
David
rooted his prayers
in the
character
God
that's the
first lesson of Psalm 120
discipleship begins when we
cry out in distress
and God is faithful
to answer us
see too often church
I've seen
that become the destination
right
the destination for the believer
right cry out to God
pray this prayer
he is faithful to answer
that
you've got your ticket
punched
so while I think
the crying out to God
and praying this prayer
that God is faithful to answer
right
I believe that to be true
but often times
we stop there
it's not wrong
it's just not the destination
it's the starting place
it's the foot out of the door
in this life of pilgrimage
to the holy city
but often
we the church in America
we're guilty of discipleship
and pilgrimage
stopping there
and why do I think that is
one
to Ryan's point this morning
I think we're
culturally programmed
to be highly individualistic people
but that's not
the language
of the New Testament
and two
we're being honest
I'm being honest
we're scared of inviting
people along
on this journey
with us
because they know
we know
that they will see
our faults
and our shortcomings
and we're gonna have
to acknowledge
as our witness
in front of someone
think back
to the picture
of stepping out
of your doorway
the hot sun
hitting your face
the dust
from the cloud
of witnesses
en route to Jerusalem
some in that group
are young
and running ahead
there might be those
caring for young children
there may be some
walking
walking in immense
joy
and others
walking in immense
grief
there are some
old
leaning on their
stats for support
each one of these
groups has something
to teach you
and probably has
something to be taught
which is why we do
this in community
we are all
on pilgrimage
together
communally
all of us
on our way
to Jesus
discipleship
doesn't stop
with the first
step out the door
it's just the
beginning of the
journey
verse 2 says
deliver me
oh Lord
from lying lips
and from a deceitful
tongue
here's another
truth
about the journey
although I've
built it up
this way
it's not just
about physical
steps
I believe
the pilgrimage
shapes our
hearts
our spirit
and the pilgrimage
shapes us
as a whole
person
the road
exposes what's
false
what's deceptive
and what's
not yet
fully under
God's control
and God's
answer
it's his
presence
faithfulness
and
it's his
community
which teaches
us to trust
in him
even when the
world around
us is not
trustworthy
but
I read that
the first time
and then I
re-read it
and
Holy Spirit
revealed something
to me
it can also
expose what is
untrustworthy
about ourselves
deliver me
oh Lord
from my
lying lips
and from
my deceitful
tongue
the psalm
closes
with a desire
for peace
I am
when I
speak
they are
for war
discipleship
is rarely
easy
ask anyone
who's
done
discipleship
sometimes
the road's
going to be
lonely
sometimes we
long for the
peace that only
comes from when
the presence of
God is near
while God's
presence might
seem like it's
high on that
mountain in
Jerusalem
I tend to
think about
it works
more like the
pillar of cloud
by day
and the pillar
of fire
by night
leading the
Israelites
through the
wilderness
during the
exile
or through
the
exodus
see can we
as God's
people pray
this with
sincerity on
our journey
when we are
threatened by
bandits and
lawlessness
along the
road of our
journey and
pilgrimage
I am
for peace
but they
are for war
but even on
that road
of walking
this journey
our steps
are not
wasted
every
conversation
hardship
every act
of patience
or courage
is forming
us
I want to
camp out here
for a second
because I
think we say
it in our
Christianese
but I don't
think we
consciously
live like it
we talked
about a
similar thought
in our
small group
the other
week
every step
every
conversation
hardship
every act
is forming
us
and I would
ask
in which
direction
are those
actions
taking
further from
God
or closer
closer
to the
destination
of our
pilgrimage
or back
to the
doorstep
of slavery
and bondage
that we
walked out
of
we talk
about
perseverance
and discipline
all the
time
especially
when it
comes to
diets
fitness
or even
sports
right
we see
the benefits
of that
but
often times
we are
unwilling
to talk
about it
when it
comes to
our
faith
especially
with
others
so we
recognize
and see
the benefits
of perseverance
and discipline
in the
world
but we
often
deny
the
sanctifying
aspects
of perseverance
and discipline
when it
comes to
the things
of God
each
decision
we make
each
act
we take
each
time
we put
one foot
in front
of the
other
on our
journey
we're
either
heading
closer
to the
heart
of God
or further
away
spiritual
growth
church
is more
like
planting
a garden
than it
is
microwaving
a dinner
but that's
what we
want
I'm being
honest
I don't
know where
you guys
are at
this is
what I
want
I want
microwavable
Christ
likeness
I want
to pop
it in
the oven
I want
to pop
it in
the microwave
and I
want
to be
just
like
Jesus
we all
do
right
it's
not the
way it
works
and we
know
that
right
we want
fast
easy
and effortless
church
the way
of Jesus
has always
been narrow
slow
and costly
we just
don't want
to admit
it
so let's
church
let's
together
stop
pretending
like we
can drift
into holiness
the same
way we
drift
into
fitness
I'm
saying
that
for me
too
stop
pretending
we can
drift
into
holiness
we are
always
being
formed
and
discipled
one way
or another
the question
is
by what
and towards
whom
this is the
slow
often hidden
work of
formation
and it
happens not
just in the
big moments
and you've
heard me
talk about
this
but in the
quiet
unseen
steps
in patience
in surrender
in community
in repentance
and in hope
I said this
the other night
at fires
as I was
kind of
prepping
this message
and I
couldn't
find a
good spot
for it
when I
was
prepping
my message
but
it
feels like
right to
say
God
delights
more
in our
perseverance
our quiet
than I think
he does
in our
flash of
zealousness
we really
like that
flash of
zealousness
right so
other people
can know
how on
fire we
are for
God
that
zealousness
doesn't
impress
me
not putting
that on
God
doesn't
impress
me
what
impresses
me
is the
quiet
faithfulness
of someone
when I
see
pastors
and
not even
just
pastors
but
Christians
finish
the race
well
that
encourages
me
over the
flash of
I got
these
ideas
it's
great
don't
hear
me
that's
wrong
but
the
perseverance
God
so let
us set
our sights
on Christ
let us
choose
to walk
this
road
that
leads
to
life
together
through
the
wilderness
on the
road
towards
the
presence
of
God
together
as
we
read
Psalm
together
today
hear
it
not
just
as
a
historic
song
of
Israel
but
as a
song
for
our
own
pilgrimage
hear it
as a
mirror
of our
journey
the
first
steps
the
struggles
along
the
way
and
the
faithful
God
who
meets
us
in the
dust
and in
the heat
our
weaknesses
Psalm 120
is the cry
at the
starting line
or even
the restarting
line
for some
Psalm
is the
traveler
the
community
the great
cloud
of
witnesses
looking
up
and
trusting
the
one
who
keeps
their
feet
moving
Psalm
reminds
us
to
step
out
and
Psalm
reminds
us
to
keep
walking
I'm
going to
ask you
to stand
with me
again
as we
read
Psalm
together
I'll
start
in the
congregation
pick up
the next
line
I
lift
my
eyes
to
the
mountains
where
does
my
help
come
from
he
will
not
let
your
foot
slip
he
who
watches
over
you
will
not
slumber
the
Lord
watches
over
you
the
Lord
is
the
shade
at
your
right
hand
the
Lord
will
keep
you
from
all
harm
he
will
watch
over
your
life
this
is
the
word
of
the
Lord
you
may
be
seated
to
where
Psalm
begins
in
distress
Psalm
begins
in
hope
it's
the
eyes
lifted
up
the
hands
open
the
heart
aware
that
God
is
not
distant
but
present
guiding
and
protecting
I
lift
my
eyes
towards
the
mountain
where
will
my
help
come
from
my
help
comes
from
whom
the
Lord
maker
of
heaven
and
earth
I
want
you
all
to
notice
the
shift
pilgrims
are
no
longer
crying
out
the
community
now
looks
up
the
focus
has
moved
from
the
struggle
around
them
over
everything
not
because
now
of our
affinity
for the
mountains
those hills
might look
like
a
pretty
postcard
does
but
for
the
ancient
traveler
I
think
they
would
be
both
dangerous
and
beautiful
the
hills
if you
will
Matt
Kucinich
and I
were talking
about this
the other
day
I
love
to
watch
documentaries
and
wonder
how
I
would
make
it
and not
very
long
usually
but
imagine
you're
a
pilgrim
in
the
desert
walking
towards
Jerusalem
these hills
could hide
robbers
they could
be dotted
with pagan
shrines
danger
lay
ahead
but
I
think
the
psalmist
says
something
pretty
inspiring
they
say
I'm
not
trusting
the
hills
I'm
looking
beyond
the
hills
to
the
maker
of
heaven
and
earth
that's
where
my
safety
comes
from
this
is
the
posture
of
discipleship
recognizing
our
limitations
but
lifting
our
eyes
to
the
one
who
never
sleeps
tires
and
never
fails
Psalm
reminds
us
that pilgrimage
is not
just about
enduring
the
road
but
trusting
the
one
who
walks
with
us
discipleship
is a
communal
journey
and as
a
community
as
brothers
and
sisters
in
Christ
we
look up
together
helping
each
other
up
watching
out
for
each
other
and
pointing
each
other
back
to
the
one
who
will
never
grow
weary
and
this
is
where
the
Psalms
of
Ascent
are
so
rich
for
us
as
a
church
because
they
call
us
to
journey
together
to
lift
our
eyes
together
to
cry
out
together
and
to
trust
together
the
pilgrimage
shapes
us
individually
but I
wouldn't
neglect
the
idea
that
the
journey
shapes
us
as
a
community
pilgrimages
were
risky
the
heat
of
the
day
cold
at
night
the
uneven
paths
with
animals
wild
any
one
of
those
things
could
take
out
a
person
the
pilgrims
sing
together
God
will
keep
me
God
will
keep
us
that's
discipleship
too
the
life
of
apprenticing
to
Jesus
is
not
self
powered
we
don't
make
it
to
the
end
because
we
are
strong
we
make
it
to
the
end
because
God
is
faithful
the
God
who
calls
keeps
us
and
he
doesn't
keep
us
in
isolation
we
love
that
because
we
never
get
challenged
in
our
own
shortcoming
the
pilgrims
didn't
travel
alone
they
moved
in
groups
for
safety
encouragement
and
for
joy
the
road
to
Zion
New
Jerusalem
is
now
as it
was
then
a
shared
road
in
the
same
way
discipleship
is
not
a
solo
expedition
we
need
each
other's
songs
prayers
presence
faithfulness
that's
why the
early
church
devoted
itself
to
fellowship
just
as much
as it
did
prayer
and
teaching
I'm
going to
plug for
Ryan here
and it's
not a
plug for
Ryan
it's
but
we
push
small
groups
here
not
because
it's
a
church
program
that we
need
to
check
off
to
look
good
and
it's
not
because
we
don't
think
you're
busy
enough
no
it's
a
conviction
that we
all share
because
you
cannot
make
this
journey
of
faith
alone
without
becoming
vulnerable
and
to
the
dangers
of the
road
by
yourself
God
walked
you
into
baptism
as a
believer
as an
individual
but
welcomed
you
out
as an
into
a new
family
a
covenant
of
believers
that
brings
me
to
this
picture
of
pilgrimage
as
discipleship
that you've
heard me
talk about
both
start
with a
call
you hear
God say
come
follow
me
both
require
intentional
steps
you don't
gradually
naturally
shift
towards
Zion
but you
walk
there
spiritual
growth
doesn't
happen
by accident
but it's
instead a
series of
small
faithful steps
in the
same
direction
both
pilgrimage
and the
steps of
discipleship
are sustained
within the
community
lone travelers
are vulnerable
but together
we find
courage
joy
and growth
in the
journey
for the
pilgrim
it's the
temple
for us
it's the
presence of
God
in his
new
kingdom
Jerusalem
Zion
and here's
the theological
truth again
that holds
all this
together
the journey
is ours
to walk
we have
that
choice
are we
inviting
God
to help
us
make
the
choices
we
do
have
control
of
but the
destination
ultimately
belongs
to God
we have
no say
in that
his
presence
and his
promise
for the
ancient
pilgrim
the journey
ended in
Jerusalem
in the
temple
courts
they would
bring
their
offerings
and
celebrate
the
feast
and
worship
in the
presence
of
God
but for
us
the
journey
continues
until
Christ's
return
but along
the way
I believe
God gives
us rest
stops
of grace
one of
those rest
stops
I believe
is communion
the Lord's
table
where we
pause
remember
and taste
the promise
of the
feast to
come
it's our
reminder
that Jesus
has already
walked
the hardest
road
the road
to the
cross
so that
we could
take a
place
at his
table
Psalm
ends
with the
promise
the Lord
will watch
over your
coming
and your
going
both now
and forever
more
it's the
sign of
the new
covenant
that Jesus
says to
us
I will
see you
through
I will
keep you
and the
destination
is secure
so where
is God
calling you
on your
next step
in your
journey of
discipleship
who are
your traveling
companions
the road's
going to be
hard
we can walk
it together
under keeping
eye of the
Lord
you didn't
grab a
communion cup on your way in,